Until now, we focused on the LoRaWAN protocol and we've explained the transmission from the end-device
to the Application Server.
So, now that the data is decrypted on the Application Server, we'll focus on retrieving this data and
storing it in our application that we call the IoT Platform.
This IoT platform is where the data will be stored and available to the end user.
It's a kind of supervision system and it can be, for example, a mobile application or a simple web
page.
The dialogue between the LoRa server and the IoT platform can be done in many different ways.
We'll explain the most common situation, which are HTTP on MQTT protocols.
For each of these two solutions, we'll make some demonstration to receive data from the end-device.
This is what we call the Uplink stream.
And of course, we will also work the other way around; from the IoT platform to the end-device.
It's what we call the downlink stream.
But before diving into these two protocols, we'll explain clearly what the IoT platform is.
And it's what we're going to do in the next video.